[sighs]
[GRACE] I'm so sick of staying
in this cramped castle.
I just want to get out
of here so badly
and discover a whole new world.
That's why I'm going
to the surface.
[RIGMOR] The surface?
That's right. Where those
creatures called humans live.
And up there, they have
much freer lives than we do.
Humans have these strange
legs which they use to walk,
and without them, they
can't even swim on land.
Oh wow, but how are
you gonna get there?
Hmm.
Although, a brand new world?
That sounds just
like a beautiful dream.
I really hope I get
to see it as well.
To see that world.
To share your dream, Grace.
Yeah. Rigmor?
[GRACE] Someday we'll
go to the surface.
I know we will.
After all, that's our dream.
[magical sound]
[sighs]
[SEA SNAKE] We need to go
deeper.
All the way down.
[♪ opening music begins]
[♪ opening music ends]
Wake up.
[gasps]
Come. We don't have time.
Follow me.
What is this place?
This is Lady Grace's
secret room.
Is this...?
[SEA SNAKE] A magic mirror.
It is useless to me
as I am unable to see,
but you should
be able to see it.
Whatever it is you
are longing for,
it will show you.
[FEMALE] Where are they?
Where have Grace and Rigmor
gone to?
Those twins just don't have
a clue that they're royal
princesses and
important to us all.
They just don't realize
they must bring light to this
castle as soon as possible.
Especially Grace.
She doesn't even have the
decency to listen to me anymore.
Only yesterday
she broke into the treasury
and didn't even stop
when I told her.
She even ransacked
the forbidden relics.
I don't know what
goes on in that mind.
Grace is pretty thoughtful
when she can be.
I often wonder if
she's really needed in
this castle in the first place.
[FEMALE] Rowan,
don't be ridiculous.
Thinking thoughts like
that will only keep
the light at a distance.
Rigmor, look!
The 2 big sticks are protruding
out of the storehouse still.
This must be what
humans look like.
I wonder why this one
has 2 dorsal fins.
They can't possibly
swim like that.
Do you know?
No idea.
But looking at these humans,
they seem to be the type
who'll try to do anything.
We should be like them,
have that same
passion to explore.
So let's get out of this
castle as soon as possible,
and then we can make
our dream come true.
Speaking of,
I found something
that will help us.
How interesting!
Go on!
Rowan!
-Oh, it's you.
-What're you doing here?
Somebody's in a bad mood.
You'll tell that hag
everything, won't you?
He wouldn't!
Rowan is on your side.
He shares your concern
for the castle.
He won't tell anyone.
[ROWAN] Our castle
is losing its light,
and it's growing
colder every day.
It won't survive
much longer like this.
That's why I admire you.
You're out in the world causing
all that chaos for
the sake of the castle.
-You're wrong, though.
-About what?
[GRACE] I don't do it for
the castle. It's because—
It's because I can—
I can feel the light and
the dreams of the world.
[magical sound]
[♪ soft music]
[gasps]
The king is—
[bubbling]
[WOMAN] We must hurry now.
The throne cannot
be vacant for long.
We need the long-lost
power of the princess.
If things continue like this,
then the castle will—
Now the fate of everything
rests on your shoulders.
You must find the
light of true love
as soon as you possibly can.
[GRACE] I'm suffocating here.
That old hag,
the castle folk.
They're all forcing this
ridiculous fate on us.
I'm sick of it.
We have to get out of this place
as soon as possible.
Then we can finally
follow our dreams.
Grace, listen, I think—
[gasps]
What is that?
This is a potion that can
turn us into humans.
I finally found it.
It was hidden away
deep in the castle.
[sighs]
This elixir can alter
the very form of life.
If we use it, we can realize our
dream of going to the surface.
Let's go together.
Our dream can finally come true.
[sighs]
[♪ soft piano music]
Surely not because of that
whole destiny thing.
[RIGMOR] That's not it.
The thing is, I've—
fallen in love with him,
with Rowan.
That's why I've decided,
I'll continue to live here
in the castle.
So, was it all a lie?
Was I the only one who thought
we shared the same dream
of going to the surface?
[RIGMOR] No!
No, Grace!
I'm leaving.
[gasps]
Just make sure
you don't forget...
your amazing dream.
The light you seek up there,
it's beautiful.
[GRACE] I know.
But now...
it's my dream and mine alone.
[♪ somber piano music]
The question is...
where should I go now?
[♪ somber music continues]
[LISA] Father,
what should I do?
Living on the land has
wounded Lara's heart so deeply.
I can't help but think,
if only the witch
hadn't given Lara legs.
My child,
Lara must come to
terms with her fate.
[♪ gentle piano music]
[footsteps]
[magical sound]
Beautiful.
Rowan, it's you.
I love you.
[magical sound]
[everybody gasping]
-It's incredible!
-Light!
[mermaids chattering]
It's the light
from the princess!
It's Lady Rigmor
and Lord Rowan!
They've united in true love!
[MALE] It's wonderful!
A new princess has been born!
[ROWAN] My love,
you are to me like
a flower in bloom.
I want to always bring you joy.
[RIGMOR] My dear one,
I'm with you for a reason.
I once was searching
for a dazzling light.
[magical sound]
[RIGMOR] Now I feel that light
deep within my heart.
It's the light of love.
I feel that light in
my heart as well.
Now that light fills
every corner of the castle,
and new princesses
are on their way.
Look at this wonderful sight.
[RIGMOR] Yes, it's
truly beautiful.
I hope this light will continue
to fill the world forever,
[RIGMOR] For all mermaids
everywhere.
[ROWAN] Yes. For all mermaids.
Lady Rigmor believes that
Lady Grace left because
of her, that it was her fault.
They were inseparable twins
for years.
It must be painful for her,
but from now on, they will
never be able to meet again.
We are beings who live our
lives purely by the light,
and humans are beings who
live only by words alone.
Humans will always reject
that which cannot be spoken.
There is but only one fate
that awaits a mermaid
who ascends to the human world.
[♪ dramatic music]
[magical sound]
[MALE] What is that form?
What are you?
Can't be. Were you...
deceiving me?
All along, you were hiding
your true hideous form!
-No, I wasn't deceiving—
-Shut up!
Monsters like mermaids
use sweet words
and lure us into their traps.
No!
No, you're wrong!
I truly love you!
How can you? You don't
even have a human heart.
[GRACE] No, you're wrong.
I am human!
You're a liar!
You use human words,
but you're a hideous monster.
[♪ dramatic music ends]
[beat]
[gasps]
[♪ dramatic music]
Grace.
[distant voices calling]
[Grace gasping and sobbing]
This can't... be real.
What have I—
Please, no.
What on earth have I just done?
[cracking]
[♪ dramatic music]
[magical sound]
[MAN 1] Hey, I found them!
[MAN 2] What is this monster?
[MAN 1] It's something evil!
-Kill it!
-Go forward!
[all clamoring]
-Get it!
-Get out of here!
[all shouting]
[ALL SHOUTING] Come on, get it!
[♪ dramatic music]
[splash]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[GRACE] Rigmor...
is this a dream?
[RIGMOR] No, it's not a dream.
I heard the voice of your
heart within my own.
And I followed the light
of the ring to find you.
[GRACE] Oh, sister...
I'm such...
[Grace sobbing]
I...
-I'm such an idiot.
-[RIGMOR] Grace...
I am also an idiot.
I just I came out here
all by myself
without even thinking about it.
[GRACE] It was
an impossible dream.
Everything I did to come here,
in the end it didn't
mean a thing!
[RIGMOR] No.
It did and still does mean
something, because in my
eyes I can still see your
beautiful, beautiful dream,
and it doesn't matter.
Whether it's on land or at sea,
it doesn't matter who,
and it doesn't matter why.
As long as we can live for love,
there will always be
light in any place.
It will never fade.
That is...
our dream.
[♪ solemn music]
[ROWAN] I will never
forget that sight.
Because of my
loathing for the witch,
along with my immense hatred
toward those murderous humans,
I established a new rule,
and that was to never
approach humans ever again.
I strictly enforced it, and
I banished the witch.
If she never had the longing
for the surface world,
then this tragedy could
have been avoided.
Therefore,
I must rid you of
the same chains
that are bound to your
heart and won't let go.
That is the rule for
those who live as mermaids.
Lara!
[gasps]
[MALE] Do not look away.
This mirror will test the
very heart of the beholder.
Watch it through everything
to the very end.
If only the witch would
just disappear forever.
[MERMAID 1] But now a new
princess has arrived.
She will serve Lord Rowan.
Another new princess born.
She'll bring the light
to the castle.
[mermaids chattering]
Welcome the arrival of my
sister, hereafter known as Lara.
[LARA] I wonder if—
Well, are humans really such
hideous creatures after all?
[SNAKE] Lady Grace,
that potion is—
Is what?
I just want to see it,
that's all.
I want to see the ending
of that foolish mermaid's story.
[magical sound]
[glass shattering]
Lady Grace.
Why?
-Hey!
-Ma'am.
Go to the surface immediately
and gather the foam.
Foam?
Not a single drop
should be left behind.
Make sure you gather all of it.
[GRACE] Lara, how did
you do it?
You protected those you loved,
even at the cost
of your own life.
You were able to
resist that blade
which sought revenge
for your wounded heart.
Why?
Compared to me,
who killed those I loved
with my own tears.
What exactly makes
you so different?
[sighs]
[magical sound]
If only I could live for love.
That would be the
most wonderful feeling.
[magical sound]
Grace.
[GRACE] No, not yet.
I won't let it end yet.
I won't.
I'm going to see
the rest of this story,
see how it plays out.
No matter what.
-Witch.
-Um.
So Lara really is
coming back to life?
Is that true?
Of course, because I drained all
of the light from her father,
and gave it to her.
Very well.
As long as I have
Lara, as long...
as her princess's
light can still shine,
that power could become
so intense that it sees
the destruction of mankind.
[thump]
You're using too much power.
You shouldn't put so many
mermaids to sleep.
It's too much.
[GRACE] Eventually,
Lara will awaken
and she will face a new trial.
So if I don't put Rowan
and the others to sleep,
they will get in her way.
[SNAKE] But still, this
power is too strong.
[GRACE] In that case, I'll
simply cast aside this body.
If I inhabit a little vessel,
then my power will
last a little longer.
I will keep waiting for her.
I will be there when Lara
wakes up once more.
[grunts]
[♪ dramatic music ends]
[♪ solemn music]
[GRACE] Hurry!
Hurry and be reborn, Lara.
I still want to see it.
Your whole story.
Because you— you are the very
last remaining light to me.
For even I,
who lost my light after taking
the life of my beloved,
even I can see it.
The one and only light.
You, out of everyone, possess
a pure and true heart.
You are the one.
who can make it happen.
The dream of the surface.
Otherwise,
if there's no light
on the land,
then why?
Why have I ended up here?
[gasps]
[MARI] It moved.
Oh...
It's not dead,
but it closed its eyes again.
Not good.
-Are you dead?
-Do shut up.
Uh.
At least let me have some
peace at the end.
Huh?
Did it just talk?
Hmm?
Hey, stop it! What do you think
you're doing?
You little brat.
Put me down right now!
You're a bit rude for a fish.
But you'll be okay.
You don't have to die,
not just yet.
[♪ closing music begins]
I see it.
[glass shattering]
I see the light.
[gasps]
I can always see it.
Such a beautiful light.
[Mari cries]
[GRACE] I can still see.
Light.
The dream.
I know.
It's still there.
[Mari sobs]
[Mari cries]
[♪ closing music ends]
[GRACE] Lara.
Mari.
[gasps]
Don't live by rules.
Live for love.
[glass shatters]
[dramatic sound]
TO BE CONTINUED